<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cool 8 Puzzle</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="solver">Solver</string>
    <string name="info">Info</string>
    <string name="how_to_play_instructions">Move the tiles into the blank space to make the pattern
        shown above, by tapping on the tile you want to move.</string>
    <string name="info_description">The 8-Puzzle was invented by Noyes Palmer Chapman around 1874.
        It was originally a 4-by-4 grid, and called the 15-Puzzle. This is a simplified 3-by-3 version. </string>
    <string name="how_to_play">How To Play</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="solved">Solved!</string>
    <string name="scramble">Scramble</string>
    <string name="reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="solver_instructions">Fill in the numbers to solve, leaving the empty space blank.</string>
    <string name="solve">Solve</string>
    <string name="solver_algorithm_description">The solver finds the minimum number of moves to solve
        a random input puzzle, using the A* graph searching algorithm, which uses heuristics to guide
        its search.
        \n\nThe heuristic function in this algorithm uses the sum of the manhattan distance
        (sum of the absolute differences of the coordinates of each tile compared to each tile on
        the solved puzzle) and the number of moves made so far. Intuitively, a move that results in a
        puzzle with tiles closer to the solved puzzle, and that reaches this state with the least
        number of moves is the best one.
        \n\nThe algorithm is implemented using a priority queue with search nodes containing a single puzzle
        state, a priority, and the previous search node. At each step, all possible nodes containing
        adjacent puzzle instances are added, and the one with lowest priority is polled. Once the solved
        puzzle is reached, the steps are retraced by calling the previous node of each search node.
    </string>
    <string name="solver_algorithm">Solver Algorithm</string>
    <string name="credits">Created with Kotlin by Calvin Liu, 2020</string>
    <string name="puzzle_solver_steps">Puzzle Solver Steps:</string>
    <string name="steps">"Steps: %1$d"</string>
</resources>